our spring fans welcome to another
我们的 Spring 粉丝欢迎来到另一个
installment of spring tips in this
在此安装Spring 提示
installment we're gonna look at the
分期付款，我们将看看
Scala programming language so let's
Scala编程语言，让我们
build a new application we'll go to
建立一个新的应用程序，我们将去
start out spring Tadeo as usual and
像往常一样开始 Spring Tadeo，
we're gonna use spring boo to that om
我们要用spring boo那个om
for their latest in greatest bits and
为了他们最新的
we're just gonna call this the let's
我们只是将其称为“让我们
call artifact just because it's a demo
呼叫工件只是因为它是一个演示
right and we'll use reactive web support
正确，我们将使用响应式Web支持
will use reactive MongoDB support and
将使用反应式MongoDB支持，并且
we'll hit generate now notice that we
我们点击生成，现在注意我们
have of course haven't specified the
当然没有指定
language here right we we don't have any
这里的语言，我们没有任何语言
default support out of the box for
开箱即用的默认支持
scholar but it's pretty trivial to add
学者，但添加起来很简单
and there's no reason you couldn't use
而且没有理由你不能使用
any language even ones that we don't
任何语言，甚至是我们不知道的语言
have here that support annotations and
在这里有支持注释和
objects on the JVM so that's sort of
JVM上的对象，这有点
what we're gonna demonstrate here in
我们将在这里展示什么
this in this video now we have a new zip
现在在视频中，我们有了一个新的邮政编码
file it's been downloaded to thee here
文件已下载到此处
ok open that up
好，打开那
all right so the first thing that we
好的，所以我们第一件事
need to do is to change the Maven build
需要做的是更改Maven构建
to reflect the fact that we're going to
反映我们将要
be working with skull and not with Java
使用头骨而不使用Java
and there's a few things that we need to
我们需要做一些事情
do here so let's walk through it
在这里做，让我们来看一下
I have pre-k incipits we can borrow so
我有可以借用的学前班，所以
the first thing we're gonna do is change
我们要做的第一件事就是改变
the build stanza right so we'll go down
构建节正确，所以我们下去
here and the build stands that contains
在这里，构建架包含
our maven plugin for spring boot which
我们的Maven spring boot 插件
we still want but we want to add one
我们仍然想要，但我们想添加一个
more plugin so I'm adding the Scala
更多插件，所以我要添加Scala
maven plug-in which is very pretty very
Maven插件非常非常非常
popular pretty popular dependency that
流行相当流行的依赖
you can use a pretty popular plugin that
您可以使用一个非常受欢迎的插件
you can use to compile scholar code and
您可以用来编译学者代码和
of course it relies upon there being
当然，它依赖于
this source means call and a source test
此来源表示通话和来源测试
Scala directory so we should see to that
Scala目录，所以我们应该注意
there are actually I wonderful can just
其实我很棒
rename this so if snicks
重命名这个，所以如果有疤痕
okay rename is that possible here
好的，可以在这里重命名
showing files
显示文件
all right
好吧
all right well we import the project
好吧，我们导入项目
okay Scala we don't need this of course
好的，Scala我们当然不需要这个
so let's get into all that and we don't
所以让我们进入所有这些，我们不
need the test code either so we'll get
需要测试代码，所以我们会得到
rid of that now we have the build plugin
摆脱了这一点，现在我们有了build插件
that's let's now import the dependency
现在让我们导入依赖项
management so we'll get that as well and
管理，所以我们也会做到这一点，
paste that here this is because we need
在这里粘贴，这是因为我们需要
this call library we need to make sure
这个通话库，我们需要确保
they have the right one true version of
他们有正确的版本
the compiler on the prospect that the
编译器希望
runtime on the classpath and this is
在类路径上的运行时，这是
because we're going to use a different
因为我们将使用不同的
project that support three active
支持三个活跃项目
streams specification including force
流规格包括力
project reactor and spring web flux but
项目反应堆和Spring 腹板流量
also will as well see later other
也将在以后看到其他
projects and they want the other
项目，他们想要另一个
projects want the slightly newer just a
项目想要稍微更新一点的
few months newer version of reactive
几个月新版本的React
streams 1.1 which is fine right we can
流1.1，这很好，我们可以
there's no reason not to use it it's
没有理由不使用它
backwards compatible so we'll add that
向后兼容，因此我们将其添加
to the class path and ensure that
上课的路径，并确保
everything gets moved up to that to that
一切都上升到那个
revision so with that let's see what
修订，让我们来看看
else we have here we have the dependents
否则我们这里有家属
we need to dip in geez themselves okay
我们需要自己泡一下
and we'll copy that to the clipboard and
然后将其复制到剪贴板，
bring in the Scala library right there
在那里带上Scala库
we go and finally we need to make sure
我们去，最后我们需要确保
that our build plugin which references
我们的构建插件引用
our properties here call it out version
我们这里的属性称为版本
actually reference is valid properties
实际上引用是有效的属性
right so I'm gonna bring those
对，所以我要带那些
properties in here as well alright so
这里的属性也很好
maven re-import and now we have a
maven重新导入，现在我们有了一个
directory structure that should work as
应该作为的目录结构
as expected so let's create a new
如预期的那样，让我们​​创建一个新的
package here we can call this the tweets
打包在这里，我们可以称之为推文
package so the domain model is gonna be
包，因此域模型将成为
something that I borrowed from some of
我从某些地方借来的东西
the
的
a very common example from light band
一个很常见的例子
right so I'll use that here so Scala
对，所以我在这里用它，所以Scala
tweets and we've got a package now to
鸣叫，我们现在有一个软件包
get a new code page we're gonna say
得到一个新的代码页，我们要说
tweets dots Scala and we'll specify
鸣叫Scala点，我们将指定
package Ryan so I'll say packages tweets
打包Ryan，所以我会说打包tweets
and we'll create some classes right the
然后我们将创建一些类
first thing they need to do is to create
他们需要做的第一件事是创建
the entry point into the Springwood
斯普林伍德的入口
application so class application spring
应用程序类 Spring
boot application okay now just as with
现在就可以启动应用程序了
Kotlin Scala programs don't really have
Kotlin Scala程序确实没有
a concept of statics so you create
静力学的概念，以便您创建
what's called an object peer like this
像这样的对象对等体
and it's object peer is going to extend
它的对象对等体将扩展
in this case it's call a pipe called app
在这种情况下，它称为管道app
and you don't have to do anything else
而且您不必做任何其他事情
you can just write code in this in the
您可以只在其中编写代码
center of that and it'll it'll work so
它的中心，它将起作用
class of application and of course the
应用类别，当然还有
second parameter or the argument so like
第二个参数或参数，例如
that very good so there's our there's
很好，所以有我们的
our arguments are is our spring
我们的论据是我们的 Spring
application itself and what we're just
应用程序本身以及我们只是
gonna use the simple domain model here
将在这里使用简单的领域模型
we're gonna use the domain of of tweets
我们将使用推文的域
right so I'm gonna store this domain in
对，所以我要将该域名存储在
the database so we need to first design
数据库，所以我们需要先设计
that domain so say Keith's class author
所以说基思的班级作者
and we'll have the handle of the author
然后我们将处理作者的问题
there we are gonna have another case
那里我们还会有另一种情况
class a hashtag tag string okay I'll
给一个标签标签字符串分类我会的
have another case class tweet which will
还有另一种案例类推文
have the text string and author author
具有文本字符串和作者作者
now a case class in Scala is a
现在，Scala中的案例类是
convenient way of defining an object
定义对象的简便方法
with simple properties that that or for
具有该或用于的简单属性
which we want to have getters setters
我们想要有吸气剂的人
and properties automatically generated
和属性自动生成
right so we get that for free just by
对的，所以我们只是免费获得
defining this this case class we can map
定义这个我们可以映射的案例类
this to you know we can use it just like
要知道，我们可以像使用它一样
any other object is just edit it has a
任何其他对象只是编辑它有一个
special benefit in the in the sky
天空中的特殊利益
language because you can also use it for
语言，因为您也可以将其用于
for pattern
图案
right which is slightly more advanced
对，这稍微先进一点
feature that you can you'll see a lot of
功能，您可以看到很多
in in the scholar world okay so I'm
在学者世界里好吧，所以我
getting MongoDB document here I want to
我想在这里获取MongoDB文档
tell Scala to turn these these fields
告诉Scala转到这些字段
these these construct our grants into
这些构成了我们的赠款
javabean property so I'll say at beam
javabean属性，所以我会说
property right so I have been property
财产权，所以我一直是财产
yeah and then finally I want to tell it
是的，最后我想告诉它
to turn this these individual things
把这些这些个别的东西
here into spring data document IDs so I
这里变成spring数据文档ID，所以我
ID and ID and we'll do the same right
ID和ID，我们将执行相同的操作
actually that's fine we can just leave
其实没关系，我们可以离开
those as they are and we can do the same
就像他们一样，我们可以做同样的事情
here right now this tweet will have a
现在此推文将有一个
nested collection of hashtags but those
主题标签的嵌套集合，但那些
hashtags will be synthesized based on
主题标签将基于
the text of the tweet itself so let's
推文本身的文字，所以让我们
create that here we'll say hashtags
在这里创建，我们将说标签
equals and it's going to be a Java util
等于，它将成为一个Java util
dot set of hashtag equals and we're
标签的点集等于，我们
gonna take the body the constructor
将身体作为构造函数
argument there the text and we'll split
在那里争论文本，我们将分开
it into that and then we'll collect the
放入其中，然后我们将收集
results so let's see dot collect
结果，让我们来看点收集
we're turning this and we'll say that we
我们正在转这个，我们会说我们
want to say that when I get the the
想说的是，当我得到
elements in the array and we want to
数组中的元素，我们想要
merge them together we're going to
将它们合并在一起，我们将
collect them together so we just say
收集在一起，所以我们只说
using pattern matching here we're going
在这里使用模式匹配
to use a convenience in pattern matching
在模式匹配中使用便利
which allows to automatically down type
允许自动向下键入
the the argument here we're going to say
这里我们要说的论点
case T if T that starts with then let's
情况T如果T以T开头，那么让我们
return a hashtag right and the way we're
正确返回主题标签和我们的方式
gonna do that is we're gonna say T dot
我们要做的就是说T点
replace all and so keep in mind we have
全部替换，因此请记住我们有
strings here and we're gonna make sure
字符串在这里，我们要确保
that whatever string we get we're gonna
无论我们得到什么弦，我们都会
replace everything that isn't a word
取代一言不发的一切
with just an empty space so our regular
只有一个空的空间，所以我们经常
expression here will be replace
这里的表达将被替换
everything that isn't this and a word
一切不是这个，一个字
with this just an empty empty space and
这只是一个空的空白空间，
this also lowercase it just to get a
这也小写它只是为了得到一个
canonical sort of definition here and
规范的定义在这里和
we'll return that to a will turn that
我们将其恢复为a
into a Scala set now this is not a Java
到Scala集合中现在这不是Java
set in order to to get that difference
设置以便获得差异
we need to actually use the Java
我们需要实际使用Java
converters type under scholar that
根据学者的转换器类型
collection and we can turn that set into
集合，我们可以将其变成
a Java set here alright so there's our
这里有一个Java集，所以我们有
or hash tags field that's also turn this
或哈希标签字段
into a bean property and there we go
变成一个bean属性，然后我们去
this will work just nicely just
这将很好地工作
perfectly with the you know your
与您完全了解您的
standard marshalling infrastructure like
标准编组基础结构
Jack's on for example now we want to
例如，杰克（Jack）现在上班了
actually have some sample data in the
实际上有一些样本数据
database so let's create a
数据库，所以让我们创建一个
initialization object and this
初始化对象和这个
initialization object is just going to
初始化对象只是要
be a application render as you've seen
如您所见，成为应用程序渲染
me do a number of times before so we're
我之前做过很多次，所以我们
going to initialize some data here and
要在这里初始化一些数据，
we're gonna return application runner
我们将返回应用程序运行程序
okay and it's a lambda it lends itself
好吧，它本身就是一个lambda
to being a lambda so you know it's gonna
成为lambda，所以你知道它会
expect arguments and it's gonna Richard
期待争论，理查德
a thrown exception and otherwise it's
抛出异常，否则是
fairly straightforward so we can
非常简单，所以我们可以
actually just define the lambda here now
实际上现在在这里定义lambda
this is the first time you're seeing me
这是你第一次见到我
to find out in custom lambda here it's
在这里找到自定义lambda
doing type in front so it already knows
在前面输入文字，所以它已经知道
that this is the application arguments
这是应用程序参数
that's expected from this this interface
这是该接口所期望的
it supports the same kind of functional
它支持相同的功能
interface mechanism that Java eight
Java八接口机制
introduced right so this is very
介绍正确，所以这是非常
convenient but in Scala functions our
方便，但在Scala功能中，我们
methods are a first-class citizen so you
方法是一流的公民，所以你
can create a lambda that doesn't have
可以创建一个没有的lambda
any relationship to a functional
与功能的任何关系
interface you can just create a lambda
界面，您可以只创建一个lambda
that that uh you know a standalone
那你知道一个独立的
lambda that exists just for the sake of
存在的lambda只是为了
an existing it doesn't have to conform
现有的，它不必符合
to a particular type so in this case
到特定类型，因此在这种情况下
we've got an we've got a bean it's gonna
我们有一个我们有一个 bean
return this this function interface and
返回此函数接口，并
implementation of and in this we're
的实现，在此我们
gonna initialize the database itself so
要初始化数据库本身，所以
let's create a repository to manipulate
让我们创建一个存储库来操作
the the tweets okay to repository using
可以使用存储库的推文
spring data again but in in Scala
Spring 的数据再次，但在斯卡拉
interfaces are a something called a
接口是所谓的
trait and they also have the ability to
特质，他们也有能力
to specify a behavior just like Java
指定类似于Java的行为
eight interfaces now can write so traits
八个接口现在可以编写，所以特质
are for our purposes the same thing as
就我们的目的而言，与
we you know as interface but they can do
我们知道您是界面，但他们可以做到
a lot more so I'm gonna say tweet
还有很多，所以我要说鸣叫
repository extends reactive Mongo
存储库扩展了反应性Mongo
repository managing entities and notice
仓库管理实体和通知
that the brackets here are they are the
括号在这里是
equivalent of the current of the angled
等效于成角度的电流
brackets in Java so it's gonna manage
Java中的括号，以便进行管理
types of tweet
推文类型
whose primary keys of type string and we
其主键为string类型，我们
can now inject this into our bean
现在可以将其注入到我们的bean中
definition TR tweet repository
定义TR推文存储库
and you know just to make short work of
而且你知道只是为了缩短
things I'm gonna i've already
我要去的事
pre-selected some some tweets that we
预选了一些我们发布的推文
can use so there are there some tweets
可以使用，所以有一些推文
from some people in the community we put
来自社区中的一些人
myself included and then two folks from
包括我自己，然后是两个人
the Scala and akka and my pin community
Scala和Akka和我的Pin社区
and we're gonna use their you know use
我们将使用他们知道的用途
that sample data this sample data here
该样本数据在这里
as our as our example set so we're gonna
作为我们的榜样，所以我们要
first of all going to call delete all
首先要通话全部删除
from you know deleting everything in the
从你知道删除的一切
database then we're gonna save
数据库，然后我们将保存
everything using this a the repository
一切都用这个仓库
passing in the tweets there then we're
在那儿传递推文，然后
gonna get the other thing that comes
会得到另一件事
everything back from the database then
然后从数据库返回所有内容
we're gonna subscribe to that data and
我们将订阅该数据，
here you see I'm you know I'm doing
在这里，你看到我，你知道我在做
fairly straightforward stuff this should
应该很简单的东西
look very familiar if you've ever used
如果您曾经使用过，看起来非常熟悉
project reactor right into our project
项目反应堆直接进入我们的项目
reactors are reactive API that underpins
反应堆是支持的反应性API
the spring Webb flux web runtime and
Spring Webb Flux Web运行时和
spring 2.0 and spring framework five and
Spring 2.0和Spring Framework 五
you have the ability at the ultimately
您最终有能力
at the end of the day to work with
在一天结束时与
reactor specific project erection
反应堆特定项目的架设
project specific types called fluxes and
项目特定类型称为磁通和
models these are subtypes of a of an
这些是模型的的子类型
interface called publisher and publisher
称为发布者和发布者的接口
code comes from the reactive streams
代码来自反应流
initiative right so we saw that
主动的权利，所以我们看到了
dependency on the craft path here we saw
我们在这里看到的对工艺路线的依赖
the reactive streams types 101 on the
反应堆上的反应流类型101
class path so we're gonna use that here
课堂路径，所以我们将在这里使用
in our code and we're gonna take
在我们的代码中，我们将采取
advantage of that that commonality there
那里的共同点的优势
we're gonna take advantage of the fact
我们将利用这一事实
that other projects integrate with
与其他项目整合
reactive streams initiative just like we
像我们一样的反应式流倡议
do for in drop right so we're gonna use
为右滴做，所以我们要用
that here we're gonna say I want to
在这里，我们要说我想
print out information about this tweet
打印有关此推文的信息
and so obviously we will use a
所以很明显，我们将使用
multi-line string here yet another thing
多行字符串在这里还有另一件事
that's really nice and inside of a scala
真的很好，在scala里面
and we'll say t-thought
我们会说
dot author dot handle and we'll print
点作者点句柄，我们将打印
out the hashtag so T dot hashtags and
删除主题标签，使T点主题标签和
then we'll print out a new string so
然后我们将打印出一个新字符串
let's see we'll say T dot txt and before
我们来看一下T点txt和
we do that let's actually also print out
我们这样做实际上还可以打印出来
a new line okay so we're just we're
换行了，所以我们就是
using a multi-line string here in Scala
在Scala中使用多行字符串
that's very convenient we're using token
我们使用令牌非常方便
you know there's a tokenization
你知道有一个标记化
mechanism that actually lets us
实际上让我们的机制
dereference in variables actually in the
实际在变量中取消引用
strings themselves I mean you know
自己串起来我的意思是你知道
they're being interpolated into the
他们被插值到
string automatically for us we've got
为我们自动设置字符串
the kind these living templates that's
这些生活模板的种类
pretty cool and then we're gonna print
很酷，然后我们将打印
it all out when we see it right and
当我们看到正确的一切时，
we're this is a consumer we're providing
我们是这是我们提供的消费者
a lambda here so should look you know
一个lambda在这里，所以应该看起来你知道
fairly straightforward if you're coming
如果你要来的话很简单
at this from from from Java 8 for
来自Java 8
example this shouldn't be too much of a
这个例子不应该太多
big of a back of a meat right
肉背很大
cognitively the only thing you'll notice
从认知上讲，您会注意到的唯一一件事
is that we have to use in equals instead
是我们必须在等号中使用
of a minus sign right Java is a minus
负号的正确Java是负号
sign equals 4 Scala but otherwise this
符号等于4 Scala，否则为
should look fairly straightforward if
如果看起来应该很简单
you if you've used Carmen this looks
你，如果你用过卡门，这看起来
fairly straightforward as well so lots
也相当简单
of lots of cool stuff going on here
这里有很多很棒的东西
let's see if that works let's go ahead
让我们看看是否可行，让我们继续
and run the application and confirm that
并运行该应用程序并确认
we have successfully been able to write
我们已经成功地写了
these six different tweets and their
这六个不同的推文及其
authors you know you can see that
您知道的作者您可以看到
reflected over here to the console to
反映到这里到控制台
the database rather okay there we are so
数据库相当好，我们就这样
there's our data you know the hashtags
有我们的数据，您知道主题标签
and the the author and the the content
以及作者和内容
of the tweet right it's all there and
正确的推文就在那里
now we want to build a service right so
现在我们想建立一个服务，所以
let's build a service so that we can
让我们建立一个服务，以便我们可以
build a REST API so we'll say class
建立一个REST API，所以我们说类
tweet service and we'll take advantage
推特服务，我们将利用
of the tweet repository and the service
信息库和服务的信息
is just added to a Java you know it's a
刚刚添加到Java中，您知道它是一个
spring object that that M is annotated
带有M的Spring 对象
with the stereotyped annotation service
使用原型注释服务
and for our first bit of functionality
对于我们的第一功能
we'll have an endpoint or a service
我们将有一个端点或服务
called tweets and all that's going to do
称为推文，这一切都将要做
is just return all the tweets but you
只是返回所有推文，但是你
know we can use that now to send up a
知道我们现在可以使用它来发送一个
REST API so I suppose the the first way
REST API，所以我想第一种方法
to do that would be to pate a rest
要做那将是休息一下
controller a spring web flex controller
控制器spring web flex控制器
here okay and we're gonna say tweet rest
好的，我们要说鸣叫休息
controller okay an endpoint here get
控制器好了，这里的端点
mapping array tweets deaf tweets and
映射数组鸣叫聋的鸣叫和
we're just going to inject the tweet
我们将注入推文
service so TR tweet service dot tweets
服务，所以TR tweet服务点tweets
all right there we go so there's our
好的，我们走了，所以有我们的
there's our rest endpoint let's go ahead
还有我们的其余端点，让我们继续
and see if that works now you'll notice
看看现在是否有效，您会注意到
that intelligence kind of hinting that I
这种智慧暗示着我
should do better I should be very
应该做得更好我应该非常
explicit about the return value here
在这里明确返回值
right and I and that's probably good
对，我，那可能很好
advice but because of this the very
建议，但正因为如此
sophisticated type inference in Scala
Scala中的复杂类型推断
this will this would have actually
这将实际上
worked had we left it as it was right so
如果我们将其正确放置就可以了
this is what it's asking me to do is to
这就是我要的
do this to be explicit and then return
这样做是明确的，然后返回
value and that's probably a good idea
价值，这可能是一个好主意
especially if you want to be sure they
特别是如果您要确保他们
don't break something on you know in
不要破坏你知道的东西
this case the runtime is the consumer oh
这样的话运行时就是消费者哦
it failed because of the porch right so
它因为门廊而失败了，所以
that's in this case the runtime was the
在这种情况下，运行时是
consumer of this method righted the
此方法的消费者对
invoker of this method but a you know
此方法的调用者，但是您知道
and I would have done the right thing
我会做正确的事
had we returned a reasonable object but
我们是否返回了一个合理的对象，但是
that may not always be the case so
并非总是如此
that's probably good advice so let's see
那可能是个好建议，让我们看看
tweets there it is there's our our
鸣叫那里是我们的
tweets that are coming from the Davis
来自戴维斯的推文
that seems to be working right now I
我现在似乎在工作
want to create another endpoint okay an
想要创建另一个端点
endpoint that just returns all of the
仅返回所有
hashtags in all of these different
所有这些不同的主题标签
tweets normalized right I want to return
推文归一化对，我想返回
the unique hashtags because some
唯一的主题标签，因为一些
hashtags up here more than once in
在这里将标签多于一次
different tweets I don't want to have
我不想拥有的不同推文
them all
商场
want to get the ones that you know I'm
想得到你知道的我
gonna get everyone tweet hashtag once
一次让所有人发推特标签
so that's create a new endpoint here
所以在这里创建一个新的端点
called hashtags deaf hashtags and in
称为hashtags聋子hashtags和
order for this to work we're gonna use
为了使这个工作，我们将使用
the akka streams library now akka
akka流库现在akka
streams is a a library from my pinned
流是我固定的一个图书馆
which was formerly called tide safe
以前称为潮汐安全区
they're the Shepherd's of the Scala
他们是斯卡拉的牧羊人
language and akka streams has some very
语言和Akka流有一些非常
interesting features some very
有趣的功能
compelling features I I think it's a for
引人注目的功能II认为这是一个
what I'm doing for this simple example I
在这个简单的例子中我正在做什么
probably could get away with just using
可能只用就可以摆脱
reactor but that said there are some
反应堆，但说有一些
integrated interesting integrations for
集成了有趣的集成
for akka streams that that go beyond you
超越你的阿卡溪流
know what we're doing here that you
知道我们在这里做什么
should perhaps investigate and that's
应该调查一下，那就是
the whole point right now we're not what
整点我们现在不是
I'm trying to demonstrate is that
我想证明的是
because it's just a JVM language and
因为它只是一种JVM语言
because we have interoperability in
因为我们在
terms of the directive streams there's
指令流的条款有
no reason that your world has to to you
没有理由你的世界对你
know sort of ignore this this treasure
知道有点忽略这个宝藏
trove of of functionality that there's a
大量的功能
lot of stuff you could use from that
您可以从中使用很多东西
community for that ecosystem and you
该生态系统的社区，而您
should absolutely do so right you can
应该绝对这样做吧
expand the richness of your application
扩展您的应用程序的丰富性
by pulling in the best of breed
通过引进最好的
components and so this is just a simple
组件，所以这只是一个简单的
example now you know in order for us to
现在的例子，您知道以便我们
to get the akka streams library in the
在中获取akka流库
craft path we need to bring in the
工艺路线，我们需要引入
dependency so it will say DEP start a s
依赖关系，因此它将说DEP开始为
copy that to the clipboard and we'll
复制到剪贴板，我们将
bring the since will say that we want to
带来了以后会说我们要
use the ARCA streams dependency version
使用ARCA流依赖版本
that has been compiled for Scala to that
已经为Scala编译的
twelve and again this you know it will
十二，这又一次，你知道它将
happen that you have different libraries
碰巧你有不同的图书馆
to compile for different versions of
编译为不同版本的
Scala because it's sometimes not easy to
Scala，因为有时不容易
keep interoperable or backwards
保持互操作性或向后
compatibility when they change the
当他们改变
language right that's you know it's just
正确的语言，就是你知道的
a fact right it's just something that
事实是对的
happens that's okay it's not a big deal
没关系，这没什么大不了的
in practice so you can see we've just
在实践中，所以你可以看到我们已经
bring in the right version we've we've
引入正确的版本，我们已经
got a property here called Scala major
在这里有一个名为Scala major的物业
that version we're using it's called
我们使用的那个版本叫做
2 out of 12 and we're bringing this so
12人中有2人是这样
now we are going to say that we want to
现在我们要说我们想
take all the data so we'll say source
取所有数据，所以我们说源
right we're gonna bring in a source type
对，我们要引入一个源类型
from extremes using the skull of DSL and
从极端使用DSL的头骨和
we're gonna say give us all of the all
我们要说给我们所有的一切
of the tweets this is a publisher might
在这条推文中，这可能是发布者
remember in reactor the flux and
记住反应堆中的通量和
monotypes extend from publisher but in
单一型从发布者延伸而来
extreme z' they have their own it has
极端z'他们有自己的
its own processing model it's on
它自己的处理模型
pipeline definition model and it's easy
管道定义模型，这很容易
enough to originate the the data that
足以产生数据
that feeds into the extreme pipeline
进入极端管道
from a reactive streams it's easy enough
从反应流中很容易
to originate the the data that feeds
生成馈送的数据
into the extreme pipeline from a
从一个极端的管道
reactive streams publisher so that's
反应性流发布者，所以
what we're doing we're saying create an
我们正在说的是创建一个
echo streams source from a reactive
来自反应堆的回声流源
streams publisher and then what we have
流发布者，然后我们拥有
is a where we have we have a collection
是我们有收藏的地方
of tweets but we don't want this we
的推文，但我们不想要这个
don't want the hashtags don't we so for
不想标签不是我们想要的
each tweet we want to get the hashtags
我们想要获取主题标签的每条推文
right and we want to say Java converters
对，我们要说Java转换器
dot as Scala set that to sets okay and
Scala将点设置为可以并设置
then we want to take the data that comes
那么我们想获取来的数据
back and we want to we want to reduce it
返回，我们想要减少它
so we want to create a a collection of
所以我们想创建一个
collections here right so we're gonna
这里的收藏，所以我们要
say a B and we're just going to join
说一个B，我们将要加入
them together right these these are
他们在一起，这些都是
collections we're going to you know add
我们将向您发送的收藏集添加
them to each other basically that's what
他们彼此之间基本上就是这样
this is doing adding collections of
这是在添加
things to each other or pending them to
彼此之间或等待它们
each other and then from there we want
彼此然后从那里我们想要
to take the limit flatten everything so
以极限压平一切
we're gonna take the collection of
我们将收集
collections and flatten it into just a
集合并将其展平为一个
collection of whatever we've got inside
我们所拥有的东西的集合
the collections right so when you use
正确的收藏，所以当您使用
the map concat callback here and we're
地图concat回调在这里，我们
gonna tell it to use this funk
会告诉它使用这个放克
called identity which basically says
所谓的身份，基本上说
given a we turn an iterable of a right
给定我们转向权利的迭代
so we're gonna that's what we doing
所以我们要做的就是
there and then finally we want to take
在那里，最后我们要带
the data that we've got coming in from
我们从中得到的数据
that source and we want to run it we
该源，我们想运行它，我们
wanted to actually terminate the the
想要实际终止
definition and do something with it well
定义并做得好
here we have a number of different
在这里，我们有许多不同的
things that we could do but what I want
我们可以做但我想要的事情
to do is I want to take the data and use
我要做的就是获取数据并使用
a sink right so I'm going to say first
正确的下沉，所以我先说
of all try and get this to get imported
所有尝试并获得进口
all right
好吧
as publisher true and in order for us to
作为发布者，真实且为了我们
use this we need to provide a
使用这个我们需要提供一个
materializer an actor materializer and
实现者实现者实现者
well the materializer mechanism in akka
很好地在阿卡实现机制
streams is it's what it's what is used
流是它用的是什么
to deploy and then run the the
部署然后运行
definition the pipeline here so it says
在这里定义管道，所以它说
you know source from publisher then
您知道发布者的来源
these processing operations happen and
这些处理操作会发生，
so on so we have to this is just a it's
所以我们必须要做的只是
a graph if you will up until here you've
一张图，如果你要一直到这里
got a graph definition but there's no
有一个图形定义，但没有
telling how where those the the the the
告诉那些在哪里
components in the in the graph will get
图中的组件将获得
executed so you talk to you to provide a
被处死，所以你跟你谈谈
materializer
物化器
well one materializer that's very
好一个物化器，非常
convenient is called an actor
方便被称为演员
materializer it's just a materializer
物化器只是物化器
the delegates to akka which is an actor
代表演员akka的代表
system that runs on in this case is
在这种情况下运行的系统是
local actor so we're gonna say we know
当地演员，所以我们要说我们知道
create some actor a kibitz you know we
创造一个演员基比兹，你知道我们
know k at the akka actor system and the
知道akka演员系统中的k
actor mid-tier eyes are based on that
演员中间层的眼睛是基于
right so a configuration beam deaf actor
对，所以配置梁聋人演员
system equals actor system dot create
系统等于actor系统点创建
beautiful scala okay then we create
美丽的斯卡拉好吧，然后我们创建
another beam here deaf actor
另一个光束在这里聋人演员
materializer
物化器
equals actor materializer dot
等于演员物化点
create this dot actor system there we
在这里创建这个点演员系统
are
是
so we've got now these two different
所以我们现在有了这两个不同的
components and we're going to take
组件，我们将采取
advantage of that mature laser here
这里成熟的激光的优势
we'll say am act or materialize right
我们会说是行事或实现权利
very good and we'll pass that in so I am
非常好，我们会通过，所以我
now notice that I'm providing here an
现在注意，我在这里提供了
implicit parameter I could define this
我可以定义隐式参数
as an implicit variable somewhere or I
作为某个地方或我的隐式变量
can just explicitly prove it pass it in
可以明确证明它通过了
here which is what I'm doing it's an
这就是我正在做的
optional parameter if there's an
可选参数（如果有）
implicit type somewhere which is say if
隐式类型在某处
there's an implicit variable defined in
在其中定义了一个隐式变量
scope then any place where that type is
范围然后该类型是
defined or whether any type any place
定义或任何类型的任何地方
where that type is needed and it's
需要那种类型的地方
marked as implicit this caller will look
标记为隐式，此呼叫者将看起来
in the enclosing scope or enclosing
在封闭范围或封闭范围内
scopes and look for something that
范围并寻找一些东西
defines that type and it will provide it
定义该类型，它将提供它
for us automatically so if you've got
自动为我们服务，如果您有
parameters that are passed into method
传递给方法的参数
calls to a number of successive method
调用多个连续方法
calls but you know you're going to
打电话，但是你知道你要
define it once and you can define it
一次定义就可以了
before you call those different method
在您调用那些不同的方法之前
calls you can define it as an implicit
调用您可以将其定义为隐式
scope thing and it'll just be
范围的东西，它将只是
automatically assumed to be the
自动假定为
parameter it's a it's a little bit magic
参数，这是一个魔术
if you haven't seen it before but it
如果您以前没看过，但是
does does make things a lot more concise
确实使事情更加简洁
to know then lends itself to building
知道然后有助于建设
really nice DSL okay so in this case so
DSL很好，在这种情况下，所以
we're just gonna be very explicit we're
我们只是非常明确的
gonna say use this actor materializer
要说用这个演员物化器
this is the one that spring is provided
这是提供Spring 的那个
for us this by the way is the
对我们来说，这是
constructor syntax you if you've used
构造函数语法，如果您曾经使用过
call comment before this will seem very
在此之前致电评论似乎非常
familiar this is a constructor it's not
熟悉，这是一个构造函数，不是
the only one of course but we're
当然唯一，但是我们
creating a constructor we're telling
创建一个我们要告诉的构造函数
Scala that we want to create a bean Java
我们要创建Java Java的Scala
JVM object that has a constructor with
具有构造函数的JVM对象
two properties one is called TR and when
两个属性之一称为TR，而当
it's called a.m. and we can reference
叫做am，我们可以参考
these constructor parameters within the
这些构造函数参数
body of method so as though we got a
方法的主体，好像我们有一个
constructor plus a field right a
构造函数加上一个正确的字段
reference there all right so that gives
参考那里没事，所以给
us back a publisher let's just be very
我们支持发行商，让我们变得非常
clear and explicit about it but it does
清楚明确，但确实可以
it gives us a publisher that we can use
它给了我们可以使用的发布者
and here we have a publisher of tweet
这里有一个tweet的发布者
and because spring web flex
而且因为spring web flex
no it natively knows what to do with
不，它本来就知道如何处理
publishers this should just work right
发布者，这应该工作正常
I'm not using reactor or anything else
我没有使用反应堆或其他任何东西
I'm just using three active streams
我只是使用三个活动流
initiative and the spring one flex with
主动和 Spring 与
API which is built around the reactive
围绕反应式构建的API
streams specification alright so let's
流规范好了，让我们
see it run this again and we only wanna
看到它再次运行，我们只想
have a rest endpoint don't Lee so we'll
有一个休息的终点不要李，所以我们会
say array of hashtags I'm gonna call it
说一个标签标签数组，我将其称为
the hashtags unique endpoint hashtags
主题标签唯一端点主题标签
publisher of ash tag equals T dot
ash标签的发布者等于T点
hashtags
主题标签
okay run that again
好吧，再次运行
hashtags unique all right
标签唯一好
so there's our our new endpoint created
所以我们创建了新的端点
using the echo streams project and so
使用回声流项目等等
we've you know we've just created a very
我们知道您刚刚创建了一个非常
simple example here right we've got a
简单的例子在这里，我们有一个
very simple example but there are
很简单的例子，但是有
several things that should stand out
应该突出的几件事
first of all this isn't all that
首先这还不是全部
different from from Kotlin or groovy or
与Kotlin或groovy或
any other sort of modern language and in
任何其他现代语言
some respect it's all that different
有些尊重，一切都不同
from from Java 8 Rande keep in mind
Java 8 Rande的开发者谨记
martin Nordisk he was martin or just
马丁·诺德（Martin Nordisk）他是马丁还是
guinea the creator of of scala was one
几内亚Scala的创建者是一位
of the people that worked on the on Java
在Java上工作的人
itself years ago so he kept a lot of the
本身，所以他保留了很多
good stuff from Java a lot of the things
Java的好东西很多
that didn't need to change haven't right
不需要改变就不对
so you noticed that we use the word
所以您注意到我们使用了这个词
extends to extend other types for
扩展以扩展其他类型
example right so you know a lot of
正确的例子，所以你知道很多
things are should feel very very
事情应该感到非常非常
familiar and there are concessions to
熟悉并且有让步
the fact that you need to be able to
您需要能够
interrupt with other JVM technologies
中断其他JVM技术
and that's why you have this ability to
这就是为什么你有这种能力
synthesize bean properties fairly
合理地合成bean属性
readily we looked at functional
随便我们看看功能
programming here you can see it's a very
在这里编程，您可以看到它非常
easy even without any sort of reactive
即使没有任何反应也很容易
context to to to process data to split
处理数据以进行拆分的上下文
it up to use pattern matching in this
它可以在此使用模式匹配
case which is what we're doing here so
情况就是我们在这里做的
using case 2 to make short work of
用案例2简化
otherwise sort of T is kind of
否则T是一种
processing this kind of this kind of
处理这种类型的
thing would have been an if statement
事情本来应该是一个if语句
and that wouldn't have been an
那不会是一个
expression and because everything in
表达，因为一切都在
Scala is an expression this becomes a
Scala是一种表达，它变成了
very clean thing that I can compose I
我可以组成的很干净的东西
can write as just a bunch of expressions
可以写成一堆表达式
one after the other as opposed to having
一个接一个地与拥有
intermediate variables right that's
中间变量是
that's convenient
那很方便
also we have these case classes and
我们也有这些案例类
these make short work of defining you
这些使定义您的工作变得很简单
know very common things GTOs or you know
知道非常普遍的事情GTO，或者你知道
things that we used is just very data
我们使用的东西只是非常数据
back and forth from one layer of the
从一层来回
stack to another these are this is
堆叠到另一个，这是
natural to write in scala but it also it
用scala编写很自然，但是它也可以
works just fine just as we expected to
就像我们预期的那样工作正常
with spring and so on with anything else
Spring ，等等
we you know you you can see that the
我们您知道您可以看到
the code that you write in spring is you
你在 Spring 写的代码是你
know it's still work still valuable
知道它仍然在工作仍然很有价值
still useful here but you can also take
在这里仍然有用，但您也可以
advantage of some of the other projects
其他一些项目的优势
out there right some of the other
还有其他一些
projects that maybe you want to take
您可能想承担的项目
advantage of or maybe
优势，也许
conversely maybe you've already got them
相反，也许你已经有了他们
and you want to also take advantage of
而且您还想利用
the spring ecosystem so this is all so
Spring 的生态系统
far we've looked at a sort of very
到目前为止，我们已经看过一种非常
traditional sort of a sort of spring
传统的 Spring
application and I'm using a rest
应用程序，我正在休息
controller here I'm using a where's my
控制器在这里我用的是我的
rest control I'm using a rest controller
休息控制我正在使用 rest controller
here to define the rest endpoints that
在这里定义其余的端点
said it's worth keeping in mind that
说值得记住的是
thanks to the functional reactive
由于功能性反应
endpoints inside of a spring 5 we can
Spring 5内的端点，我们可以
also build us a different way we can say
也让我们用一种不同的方式说
class tweet route configuration right so
类推文路由配置正确
tweet route configuration it's just a
鸣叫路由配置，这只是一个
configuration object and here I'm gonna
配置对象，在这里我要
define a route definition rather
定义路线定义
functions dot route and we'll say and
功能点路线，我们会说和
being of course and what we'll do here
当然，我们将在这里做什么
instead is we're gonna say they want to
相反，我们要说他们想
inject the Twitter the tweet service so
向Twitter注入推文服务，以便
there's this and we'll say that we want
有这个，我们会说我们想要
to make an HP get call so request
打个惠普电话，所以要求
predicates don't get and we'll say
谓词没有得到，我们会说
tweets and I have to provide a handler
鸣叫，我必须提供处理程序
function again this is a fairly easy
再次运行，这是相当容易的
thing to do because it's a functional
要做的事情，因为它是功能
interface and I'm going to say request
界面，我要说要求
server response dot ok dot body equals
服务器响应点ok点主体等于
tweet service dot tweets specifying for
推特服务点推特指定
the second parameter here that it's a
这里的第二个参数是
class of tweet ok
好的推文类
alright so there's that now several
好了，现在有几个
things are happening here that it's kind
事情在这里发生，这是一种
of worth understanding first of all we
首先值得我们了解
have a lot of extra types here we have
这里有很多额外的类型
you know predicated types or qualified
您知道谓词类型或合格的
types type references so we can use the
输入类型引用，以便我们可以使用
equivalent of static imports here by
等价于此处的静态导入
saying import all members of that that
说导入那个的所有成员
that makes it a fair bit cleaner right
这使得它更干净一点
look at that also we have a lambda here
看看那边我们也有一个lambda
but I don't really care about this
但我真的不在乎
parameter I'm not using it at all so
参数我根本不使用它
really it's just useless I can just drop
真的没用我可以放下
the name and it's very common in Scala
名称，在Scala中很常见
to see underscore that just says give it
看下划线，只是说给它
an any old name yeah we are
是任何旧名字，是的
acknowledging that it's there but we
承认它在那里，但我们
don't care about it so it's a
不在乎，这是一个
unimportant okay so that's one route now
没关系好吧，这就是现在的路线
I I want to have the other route for the
我想有另一条路线
hashtag so I'm gonna create a another
标签，所以我要创建另一个
route get tweets I'm gonna call this
路线获取推文，我将其称为
hashtags unique unique and same as
主题标签唯一唯一且与
before okay dot body tweet service dot
好的点之前，身体鸣叫服务点
hashtags class of hashtag alright there
hashtags类的hashtag在那里
we are so now if we run this
如果运行此命令，我们现在是如此
configuration you know this is
你知道这是配置
functional reactive style of building a
功能反应式建筑
REST API is I think very convenient so
我认为REST API非常方便
much more concise in this case so let's
在这种情况下更加简洁，让我们
go ahead and restart that now much more
继续并立即重新启动
concise in this case and ultimately get
在这种情况下简明扼要，最终得到
the same result right it's just just a
同样的结果，只是一个
matter of style just a matter of what
风格的问题只是什么的问题
you prefer all right so we've looked at
您希望可以，所以我们已经研究了
a you know we've looked at it scholar we
一个你知道我们看过它的学者我们
looked at setting up a new project in
看着在建立一个新项目
Scala we built a simple REST API and
Scala我们构建了一个简单的REST API，
then we turn it into a functional
然后我们把它变成一个功能
reactive arrest API if you saw any of my
反应性逮捕API（如果您看到了我的任何
previous videos or talks on spring 5 and
spring 5和以前的视频或讲座
spring webflix that shouldn't be all
Spring 的webflix不应该全部
that unfamiliar to you and if you've
对你不熟悉的，如果你已经
seen any any of my previous talks on
看过我以前的任何演讲
using common with spring and how this
与 Spring 共同使用以及如何
shouldn't feel all that unfamiliar to
不应该感到不熟悉
you and if you've seen any of my talks
你，如果你看过我的演讲
on using spring booth and again that
关于使用 Spring 展位，然后再次
shouldn't feel all that unfamiliar to
不应该感到不熟悉
you so really Scala is a nice language
你真的真的Scala是一种很好的语言
it's you know it's just a it's a little
你知道那只是一点点
different here and therefore the common
这里不同，因此共同点
things that you're likely going to do
您可能要做的事情
especially when interacting with the the
特别是在与
spring ecosystem if you've got
Spring 生态系统（如果有）
the patience to set up what small things
耐心架设什么小东西
we had to set up here to get the the
我们必须在这里设置才能获得
builds going then you can be quite
建立下去，那么你可以很
productive very quickly and I know a lot
我很快就知道了很多
of people that are using many languages
使用多种语言的人群
besides Java you know a lots of
除了Java外，您还了解很多
different angle just besides Java with
除了Java与其他角度不同
with the spring ecosystem so hopefully
充满希望的 Spring 生态系统
this gets you started and productive so
这使您开始工作并富有成效，所以
with that thanks for watching and we'll
感谢您的收看，我们将
see you next time
下次见
you
您